<?xml version="1.0"?>
<hwt_help>
  <entry id="gloss_more_info">
    <label>More information about Climate Equity Scorecards</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;Each &lt;em&gt;Equity Scorecard&lt;/em&gt; offers a quick look at a country&amp;#8217;s international mitigation pledge, its formally professed willingness to act to stabilize the global climate. This pledge is expressed as a percentage, which is calculated by comparing the country&amp;#8217;s pledge to its &amp;#8220;fair share&amp;#8221; of the international effort needed to close the gap between the current global emissions pathway and one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/glossary.php#gloss_path&quot;&gt;global mitigation pathways&lt;/a&gt;. The country&amp;#8217;s fair share is calculated within the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; (GDRs) effort-sharing framework, and is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/glossary.php#gloss_responsibility&quot;&gt;responsibility&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/glossary.php#gloss_capacity&quot;&gt;capacity&lt;/a&gt; of all countries to contribute to the general effort of stabilizing the climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Click here for:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/how.php&quot;&gt;A quick guide to interpreting these scorecards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/politics.php&quot;&gt;A few notes about the politics of fair-shares effort sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard_dev/warning.php&quot;&gt;Warning: We&amp;#8217;re not scoring national actions, but only national &amp;#8220;pledges&amp;#8221; to act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: at any point, the user may click though to the underlying &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/calculator_dev/&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights calculator&lt;/a&gt; for much more detail, and to examine and adjust a number of the controlling parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This system is still under development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_path">
    <label>Level of Global Ambition</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Equity Scorecards&lt;/a&gt; system evaluates national pledges relative to the global effort that will be needed to achieve a target &lt;strong&gt;global mitigation pathway&lt;/strong&gt;. Various target global emissions pathways can be used. They vary by level of ambitiousness, extent of risk, and whether effort is front-loaded or back-loaded, for example. We have chosen to highlight three mitigation pathways in these scorecards. (Many others, including one that&amp;#8217;s more ambitious than the AOSIS pathway, are available in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/calculator_dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDRs calculator&lt;/a&gt;, which underlies the &lt;em&gt;Scorecards&lt;/em&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;dl&gt;
                &lt;dt&gt;AOSIS&lt;/dt&gt; 
                &lt;dd&gt;This is the most ambitious global mitigation pathway with high-level political support. It is drawn from the negotiating position of the Alliance of Small Island States (AOSIS), which requires &amp;#8220;global greenhouse gas emissions to peak by 2015 and decline thereafter&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions by more than 85&#37; below 1990 levels by 2050.&amp;#8221;&lt;/dd&gt;
                &lt;dt&gt;IPCC 2&#176;C Likely (barely)&lt;/dt&gt; 
                &lt;dd&gt;This, our moderate-ambition reference pathway, is &lt;em&gt;just barely&lt;/em&gt; stringent enough to meet the IPCC guidance for an event or phenomenon that is likely to occur. Which is to say that, by current reckoning, it has a 66&#37; chance of holding mean planetary warming below 2&#176;C.
                &lt;/dd&gt;
                &lt;dt&gt;2&#176;C coin flip&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;This global mitigation pathway has a cumulative budget that suggests a roughly 50&#37; chance of temperatures rising above 2&#176;C. This assessment is made in accordance with the analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v458/n7242/full/nature08017.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meinshausen et al (2009)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
            &lt;/dl&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_pledge">
    <label>Type of Pledge</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;Many countries have expressed their national emissions mitigation pledges in the form of an &lt;em&gt;unconditional&lt;/em&gt; pledge and a &lt;em&gt;conditional&lt;/em&gt; pledge. The unconditional pledge is of lower ambition, but will be met unilaterally. The conditional pledge is higher ambition, but is conditional on other countries satisfying certain requirements relating to increasing their own ambition with respect to mitigation pledges and/or the provision of finance and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_fair">
    <label>Fair Share</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Equity Scorecards&lt;/em&gt; system assesses a country&amp;#8217;s pledges by comparing them to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; based estimate of its fair share of the global climate effort. GDRs is an effort-sharing framework that aims to provide a plausible, rigorous and transparent quantification of the commitment by &lt;a href=&quot;http://unfccc.int/resource/docs/convkp/conveng.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change&lt;/a&gt; signatories to &amp;#8220;protect the climate system for the benefit of present and future generations of humankind, on the basis of &lt;strong&gt;equity&lt;/strong&gt; and in accordance with their &lt;strong&gt;common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#8221; (Note, from any &lt;em&gt;Scorecard&lt;/em&gt;, the &amp;#8220;more results for this country&amp;#8221; link takes you to the GDRs calculator, where you can examine and experiment with a much more detailed analysis).&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_dom">
    <label>Pledged Effort</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;Nations can act to protect the climate system in one of two ways. They can act within their own borders, and they can act by providing international support to other countries. There are of course numerous complexities involved in qualifying and quantifying national actions, but at the end of the day they will have this dual aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do not attempt to estimate levels of domestic effort, but rather take authoritative estimates of pledged effort &amp;#8220;off the shelf&amp;#8221; as they become available. This raises an important caveat &amp;#8211; the scores here are only meaningful to the extent that national pledges are made in good faith. On this matter, we attempt no judgments. Also note that in some cases a country is judged to be pledging NO effort. This is typically because it has pledged only to an emission intensity target that is smaller than its projected &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_bau&quot;&gt;business-as-usual&lt;/a&gt; rate of intensity improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International effort will also be essential in any successful climate regime, but to our knowledge, no nations have yet made international pledges that are precise enough to score. This is because the scores here reflect pledged effort in 2020, not (cumulative) pledged effort before 2020. The situation on this front will evolve rapidly in the years ahead. If and when it clarifies to the necessary point, international efforts will be added to these scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <!--<entry id="gloss_intl">
    <label>Pledged International Support</label>
    <text>
                  &lt;p&gt;Nations can act to protect the climate system in one of two ways. They can act within their own borders, and they can act by providing international support to other countries. There are of course lots of complexities involved in qualifying and quantifying actions, but at the end of the day they have this dual aspect. International support is a kind of effort that a nation makes outside its own borders. It comes in many forms but can typically be reported either in monetary terms or in terms of tons mitigated. We don&amp;#8217;t attempt to estimate national levels of international support, but rather take authoritative estimates of pledged support &amp;#8220;off the shelf&amp;#8221; as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>-->
  <entry id="gloss_gap">
    <label>Pledge Gap</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;The gap shown in these &lt;em&gt;Equity Scorecards&lt;/em&gt; represents the difference between a country&amp;#8217;s pledged mitigation and its &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_fair&quot;&gt;fair share&lt;/a&gt; of the global effort.&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_bau">
    <label>Business as Usual</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;Business-as-Usual baselines (&amp;#8220;Business-as-Usual&amp;#8221; pathways) are based on projected emissions from McKinsey and Company (&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Version 2.1&lt;/a&gt;). We update and calibrate McKinsey&amp;#8217;s projections to be consistent with the most current available annual emissions data, based on fossil fuel CO2 from &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;CDIAC&amp;#8217;s data&lt;/a&gt;, non-CO2 GHGs from &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;UNFCCC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;USEPA&lt;/a&gt;, and land-use CO2 from &lt;a href=&quot;http://cait.wri.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Climate Analysis Indicators Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;See more detailed BAU documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_ei">
    <label>Emissions Intensity</label>
    <text>
      &lt;p&gt;Emissions Intensity is a measure of the efficiency of a country&amp;#8217;s economic activity, in terms of greenhouse gas emitted per unit of economic output. It is defined as greenhouse-gas emissions divided by GDP, and can be calculated either in CO2-only terms or in terms of &amp;#8220;all greenhouse gases.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
    </text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_more_results">
   <label>More Results for This Country</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;This link directs you to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/calculator_dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDRs calculator&lt;/a&gt;, where you can see and experiment with an analysis that is much more detailed than the one available in this &lt;em&gt;Scorecards&lt;/em&gt; interface.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>
  <entry id="gloss_responsibility">
   <label>Responsibility</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; defines responsibility &amp;#8211; contribution to the climate problem &amp;#8211; as the sum of all emissions corresponding to consumption above the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_dev_threshold&quot;&gt;development threshold&lt;/a&gt;. Emissions corresponding to consumption below that threshold are associated with basic consumption and therefore exempt from any contribution to national climate obligations. Responsibility is accumulated, in the GDRs standard case, from a 1990 start date. To the extent that emissions before the start date contributed to current &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_capacity&quot;&gt;capacity&lt;/a&gt;, they are accounted for implicitly in the capacity measure. To calculate national obligation, GDRs combines responsibility and capacity to compute a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_rci&quot;&gt;Responsibility and Capacity Index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>
  
  <entry id="gloss_capacity">
   <label>Capacity</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; defines capacity as income not demanded by the necessities of life, so it is considered available to support the common global mitigation and adaptation effort. Aggregate capacity is calculated as the sum of all individual incomes, excluding income below the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_dev_threshold&quot;&gt;development threshold&lt;/a&gt;. This capacity is combined with &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_responsibility&quot;&gt;responsibility&lt;/a&gt; to calculate a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_rci&quot;&gt;Responsibility and Capacity Index&lt;/a&gt;, which is taken as a measure of obligation to act. Note that capacity, as a measure of national wealth, is an indirect measure for historical emissions.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>

 <entry id="gloss_rci">
   <label>Responsibility and Capacity Index (RCI)</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; combines measures of &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_responsibility&quot;&gt;responsibility&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_capacity&quot;&gt;capacity&lt;/a&gt; (using, in the standard case, a 50/50 weighting) into a composite indicator of national obligation called the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_rci&quot;&gt;Responsibility and Capacity Index&lt;/a&gt;, or RCI. RCI is used to compute the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_fair&quot;&gt;fair shares&lt;/a&gt; division of global mitigation costs in the GDRs framework. Because both responsibility and capacity are calculated in terms of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org/scorecard/glossary.php#gloss_dev_threshold&quot;&gt;development threshold&lt;/a&gt;, a country&amp;#8217;s RCI is indirectly affected by its internal income distribution, as well as by wealth and historical emissions. GDRs, interpreted as a tax, is moderately progressive. A dollar of income that is just above the development threshold is taxed at the same rate as a dollar earned by a billionaire.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>
  
  <entry id="gloss_dev_threshold">
   <label>Development Threshold</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;The development threshold is in many ways the key to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdrights.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greenhouse Development Rights&lt;/a&gt; framework. It defines an income threshold below which an individual, whatever country they may reside in, is taken to be exempt from international climate-related obligations. This threshold is emphatically not an &amp;#8220;extreme poverty&amp;#8221; line, which is typically defined to be so low ($1 or $2 a day) as to be more properly called a &amp;#8220;destitution line.&amp;#8221; Rather, it is set to be much higher ($20 per person per day, or $7,500 per person per year), which is a bit above a reasonably-defined &amp;#8220;global poverty line.&amp;#8221; That is to say, it reflects a level of welfare that is beyond basic needs but well short of today&amp;#8217;s levels of &amp;#8220;affluent&amp;#8221; consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>
  
  <entry id="gloss_credits">
   <label>Acknowledgements</label>
   <text>&lt;p&gt;The Greenhouse Development Rights framework was developed by Tom Athanasiou &amp; Paul Baer of EcoEquity and Sivan Kartha &amp; Eric Kemp-Benedict of the Stockholm Environment Institute. Most of the programming on the GDRs Scorecards and Calculator systems was also done by Eric, with the assistance of Douglas Wang. Tyler Kemp-Benedict did most of the user-interface design and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continued funding for the GDRs project has been provided by the Stockholm Environment Institute, the Rockefeller Brothers Fund and Christian Aid. Major funding for the Equity Scorecards project was provided by the Minor Foundation for Major Challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;d also like to thank Kirk Smith, who as far as we can tell invented the Responsibility and Capacity Index. (We thought we had, but in fact Kirk beat us by over a decade!) See Kirk R. Smith, Joel Swisher, and Dilip R Ahuja, &amp;#8220;Who pays (to solve the problem and how  much)?,&amp;#8221; in Peter Hayes and Kirk Smith (eds.), &lt;em&gt;The global greenhouse regime: Who pays?&lt;/em&gt;, United Nations University Press/Earthscan, London, 1993.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
  </entry>
  
</hwt_help>
